Inventory of the Kenneth R. Hansen Papers, 1948-1982
Hoover Institution Archives
- Reports (Folder 29)
  - Bangladesh and Singapore, 1980, undated (Folder 29)
    Includes transportation outlines
  - Committee on Finance and Monetary Affairs of the National Citizens Commission on International Cooperation, 1965 (Folder 29)
    Includes correspondence
- Speeches and writings by Hansen (Folder 29)
  - "Remarks on New Trade Program," Commonwealth Club of California, 1962 (Folder 29)
  - "European Integration and U.S. Government Policy," World Affairs Council of Northern California, 1962 (Folder 29)
  - "Comparison of Government and Private Management: Valid and Invalid,", 1967 (Folder 29)
- PTRC Summer Annual Meeting papers, 1980 (Folder 29)
- Volvo (Folder 29)
  - Lahore Transportation Project, initial study, 1979 (Folder 29)
  - Iran transportation, proposal, 1977 (Folder 29)
- Stanford University Hospital facilities plan, 1980 (Folder 29)
- Correspondence (Folder 30)
  - General, 1955-1980 (Folder 30)
  - Bureau of the Budget, 1962-1963 (Folder 30)
  - Iran, 1973-1976 (Folder 30)
    Includes DeKalb Agricultural Research materials
- Speeches and writings by Hansen, 1968-1969, undated (Folder 30)
  Includes UC Berkeley programs
- Reports (Folder 30)
  - Suburbs, 1967-1970 (Folder 30)
  - Bechtel and FMC, Regional development program for Cukurova, Turkey, 1970 (Folder 30)
  - High fructose corn syrup, 1975 (Folder 30)
  - Volvo, Malaysian armored vehicle support, 1980 (Folder 30)
  - Volvo, Lahore Transportation Project, 1979 (Folder 30)
  - DeKalb Agricultural Research, Iran report, 1975 (Folder 30)
- Photographs of Hansen and presentations, 1965 (Folder 30)
- Stanford University Hospital, correspondence, reports and meeting minutes, 1980 (Folder 31)
- Personal file of Hansen (Folder 31)
  - Passport, 1964 (Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Folder 31)
  - Speeches and writings, 1971, undated (Folder 31)
- Volvo, Iran urban transport reports and documents, 1976-1977 (Folder 31)
- Annual reports (Folder 31)
  - ALZA Corporation, 1974-1975 (Folder 31)
  - Development Bank of the Philippines, 1977 (Folder 31)
- International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (World Bank), Morocco tourism report, 1969 (Folder 31)
- Doxiadis Associates, Edison Center development plan, 1971 (Folder 32)
- Iran reports and correspondence, 1973 (Folder 32)
- Volvo, Lahore Transportation Project, reports, 1978 (Folder 32)
- Singapore mass rapid transit studies, reports, correspondence, notes, 1974-1981 (Folder 32)
- Volvo, Lahore Transportation Project, agreement, 1978 (Folder 33)
- Tehran Development Council Secretariat, Iran report, 1976 (Folder 33)
- Printed matter (Folder 33)
  - General, 1971-1980 (Folder 33)
  - Commission on College Geography resource papers, Association of American Geographers, 1971-1973 (Folder 33)
- Reports (Folder 34)
  - World Bank, Egypt, 1978 (Folder 34)
  - Development reports, 1967-1972 (Folder 34)
    Includes California Bay Area and Latin America
  - Singapore mass rapid transit studies files, 1980 (Folder 34)
    Includes clipping, correspondence, reports, working papers
- Reports (Folder 35)
  - General development reports and papers, 1972-1981 (Folder 35)
  - U.S. Multinational Pharmaceutical Corporation, 1976 (Folder 35)
  - Singapore aerobus, 1979 (Folder 35)
  - Singapore mass rapid transit studies, 1980 (Folder 35)
  - Development Bank of the Philippines, 1980 (Folder 35)
  - Report on World Bank, science and technology, 1972 (Folder 35)
  - Volvo, Angola transportation, 1979 (Folder 35)
- Proposal to National Science Foundation on satellite delivery of continuing education, 1980 (Folder 35)
- Dames & Moore, correspondence, 1979 (Folder 35)
- Reports (Folder 36)
  - Volvo, Lahore Transportation Project, 1980 (Folder 36)
  - World Bank, Egypt, 1980 (Folder 36)
- Reports (Folder 37)
  - Development reports, 1967-1977 (Folder 37)
  - Volvo, Lahore Transportation Project, 1978-1980 (Folder 37)
- Adlai Stevenson Institute Fellow's Presentation, Sanford Ungar, 1973 (Folder 37)
- World Bank Staff Working Papers, 1978 (Folder 37)
- "Pharmaceuticals for Developing Countries" conference proceedings, Institute of Medicine, National Academy of Sciences, 1979 (Folder 37)
- Singapore mass rapid transit studies, reports (drafts), correspondence, and notes, 1980-1981 (Folder 37)
- Singapore mass rapid transit studies, correspondence, memoranda, notes, and reports, 1980-1981 (Folder 38)
- Clippings by Hansen, 1968 (Folder 39)
- Singapore mass rapid transit studies, reports, 1977-1980 (Folder 39)
- Development reports (Folder 39)
  - General, 1971-1975 (Folder 39)
  - Banking, 1970-1976 (Folder 39)
  - International Industrialization Institute, 1972 (Folder 39)
- Ad Hoc Panel to Study the Need and Feasibility for an International Industrialization Institute, agenda binders, papers, reports, notes, correspondence, 1972 (Folder 40)
- Development reports and papers (Folder 40)
  - General, 1968-1970 (Folder 40)
  - Doxiadis Associates report, 1971 (Folder 40)
  - World Bank Staff Working Papers, 1979 (Folder 40)
- Speeches and writing by Hansen (Folder 40)
  - Transfer of Technology Between the Developed and Less-Developed Countries, 1972 (Folder 40)
- Reports (Folder 41)
  - World Bank development reports, 1978-1979 (Folder 41)
  - Singapore mass rapid transit studies, 1980 (Folder 41)
  - Volvo, Lahore Transportation Project and Peru project, 1978-1980 (Folder 41)
- Dames & Moore, engineering bulletin, 1980 (Folder 41)
- Reports (Folder 42)
  - World Bank development reports, 1976-1981 (Folder 42)
  - Volvo, undated (Folder 42)
  - Singapore mass rapid transit studies, 1980 (Folder 42)
- Analysis of World Bank as a technological institution, draft, 1980 (Folder 43)
- Doxiadis Associates, Great Lakes study, 1970 (Folder 43)
- Clippings by and about Hansen, 1967-1968 (Folder 43)
- U. N. conference paper by Hansen, undated (Folder 43)
- Development correspondence and reports, 1968-1974 (Folder 43)
  Includes reports on Sudan and reports from Stanford Research Institute
- Singapore mass rapid transit studies, reports, clippings, correspondence, notes, invoices, 1974-1981 (Folder 44)
- Volvo, correspondence and reports, 1979-1981 (Folder 44)
  Includes correspondence with family
- Agricultural reports and seminars, 1977-1978 (Folder 44)
- Correspondence, 1973-1980 (Folder 44)
- Reports (Folder 45)
  - Stanford Research Institute, Italy, undated (Folder 45)
    Co-authored by Hansen
  - Iran Public Sector Project, 1975 (Folder 45)
  - Doxiadis Associates, Michigan highway plan, 1970 (Folder 45)
  - Bureau of the Budget, staff report on Survey of the Alliance for Progress Program in Brazil, Argentina, Chile, and Bolivia, 1962 (Folder 45)
- Hansen awards, undated (Folder 45)
- Pugwash Conference, proceedings, 1969 (Folder 45)
- Reports (Folder 46)
  - Atlantic Company, Brazil, 1956 (Folder 46)
  - Doxiadis Associates, report for Detroit Edison Company, 1970 (Folder 46)
  - Mutual Defense Assistance Control Act of 1951, reports, 1953-1955 (Folder 46)
  - Suburbia, undated (Folder 46)
- Speeches and writings by Hansen, 1966-1968 (Folder 46)
- Biographical file, 1935-1954, undated (Folder 46)
  Includes clippings, contracts, and awards
- Correspondence (Folder 46)
  - General, 1967-1980 (Folder 46)
  - Bird, Richard A., 1971-1972 (Folder 46)
- Conference and seminar material, 1966-1967 (Folder 47)
  Includes speeches and writings by Hansen, and materials from the Executive Seminar Center
- Correspondence, Edward Mason (Harvard Economic Advisory Group to Iran), 1958-1960 (Folder 47)
- Volvo, Lahore Transportation Project, reports, 1979 (Folder 48)
- Dames & Moore, memoranda and reports, 1977-1978 (Folder 48)
- Agriculture reports, 1975 (Folder 48)
- Seminar materials, 1967 (Folder 48)
- Singapore mass rapid transit studies, clippings and correspondence, 1980 (Folder 48)
- Malaysia armored vehicle maintenance support program, outline, 1980 (Folder 48)
- Statement for PhD exam, Eric Hansen, 1979 (Folder 48)
- Development reports (Folder 49)
  - General, 1967-1978 (Folder 49)
  - World Bank, 1971-1979 (Folder 49)
    Includes report on Philippines
  - Latin America, 1972 (Folder 49)
- Reports (Folder 50)
  - Iran Plan & Budget Organization, National Spatial Strategy Plan, 1976 (Folder 50)
  - Development reports, 1967-1977 (Folder 50)
- Reports (Folder 51)
  - Iran Plan & Budget Organization, National Spatial Strategy Plan, 1976-1977 (Folder 51)
  - Philippines reports, 1976-1978 (Folder 51)
- Dames & Moore, memoranda, meeting minutes, and reports, 1976-1978 (Folder 51)
- Dames & Moore, memoranda, correspondence, and attachments (including reports), 1976-1979 (Folder 52)
- Volvo, Lahore Transportation Project, correspondence, reports, agreement, and outlines, 1977-1980 (Folder 53)
- Bechtel and FMC, Regional development program for Cukurova, Turkey, report and contract, 1970 (Folder 53)
- Stanford University Medical Center, memoranda, 1979 (Folder 53)
- Speeches and writings by Hansen (Folder 53)
  - A Center for the Advancement of Management Sciences, undated (Folder 53)
- Correspondence, 1961-1973 (Folder 53)
- Singapore mass rapid transit studies, notes, 1980 (Folder 53)
- Paper by Edward Mason, 1980 (Folder 53)
- Dames & Moore, papers, 1980 (Folder 53)
- Dames & Moore, memoranda and correspondence, 1977-1978 (Folder 54)
- Doxiadis Associates, correspondence, 1971-1972 (Folder 54)
- Valtur, correspondence and reports, 1971-1972 (Folder 54)
- "Underdevelopment or Liberalization," paper including Hansen's comments, 1968 (Folder 54)
- Management conferences and seminars (Executive Seminar Center) materials, 1967-1969 (Folder 54)
  Includes remarks by Hansen
- Stanford Law School, East-West Trade proceedings, 1966 (Folder 54)
- Conference and seminar material, 1965-1967 (Folder 55)
  Includes speeches and writings by Hansen, conference materials, and correspondence
- Sanda Corporation, 1975 (Folder 55)
- Correspondence and reports (Folder 55)
  - General, 1968-1973 (Folder 55)
  - Warnett Kennedy Association, 1972 (Folder 55)
  - Syntex Corporation (Carl Djerassi), 1972 (Folder 55)
  - Optics Technology, Inc., 1972 (Folder 55)
  - National Academy of Engineering, 1972 (Folder 55)
  - Murray, Gordon, 1971 (Folder 55)
- Singapore mass rapid transit studies, reports, 1980 (Folder 55)
- Planews issue on Singapore transportation (Mass Rapid Transit), 1980 (Folder 56)
  Includes article by Hansen
- Volvo, Iran, Peru, and Malaysia transportation reports, 1976-1980 (Folder 56)
- Iran Development Consortium, Greater Bandar Abbas Area development plan, 1969 (Folder 56)
- Correspondence, Edward Mason (Harvard Economic Advisory Group to Iran), 1958-1961 (Folder 56)
- Volvo transportation reports (Folder 57)
  - Lahore Transportation Project, 1979-1980 (Folder 57)
  - Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, 1980 (Folder 57)